which can provide information on when it's safe to eat. And our analyses indicate that fish simply copying other fish in their social network could account for over 60 percent of the algae eaten by the fish community, and thus could be critical to the flow of energy and resources through coral reef ecosystems. But these findings also suggest that overfishing, a common problem in coral reefs, not only removes fish, but it could break up the social network of remaining fish, which may hide more and eat less algae because they're missing critical information. And this would make coral reefs more vulnerable than we currently predict. So remarkably, fish social networks allow the actions of one to spread to many and could affect entire coral reefs, which feed millions of us and support the global economy for all of us. Now, our discovery points us towards better ways to sustainably manage coral reefs, but it also shows us, we humans are not just affected by the actions of other humans, but we could be affected by the actions of individual fish on a distant coral reef through their simple copying behavior. Thank you. (Applause)
que pueden dar información sobre el momento más seguro para comer. Nuestra investigación indica que este simple comportamiento imitativo entre peces de distinta especie en una misma red social los induciría a comer más del 60 % de las algas. Esto puede ser fundamental para el flujo de energías y recursos a través de los ecosistemas de los arrecifes de coral. Pero este descubrimiento sugiere también que la sobrepesca --un problema muy común en los arrecifes de coral-- no solo elimina peces, sino que puede romper la red social de los peces que quedan, que estarían más ocultos y comerían menos algas porque les faltaría información esencial. Y de esta manera, los arrecifes de coral se volverían más vulnerables de lo que actualmente se predice. Notablemente, las redes sociales de los peces hacen que la acción de un pez se multiplique entre otros y de este modo pueden afectar arrecifes enteros, que son fuente de alimento de millones de personas y el sustento de la economía global de todos. Ahora bien, este descubrimiento nos indica que debemos lograr un mejor manejo sustentable de los arrecifes de coral, pero también nos muestra que los humanos no estamos influenciados solamente por la acción de otros humanos, sino también por la acción de peces individuales en un lejano arrecife de coral a través de su simple comportamiento de imitación. Gracias. (Aplausos)